masslottery.com 2009-08-30

# Massachusetts State Lottery - About the Lottery

### Privacy Policy

Welcome to the Massachusetts State Lottery web site. Your privacy, and the security of your personal information, is important to us. When you visit this web site, we may collect the following information about your visit: 

  * Anonymous statistics as you browse the site.
  * Personal information that you knowingly give to us.

This privacy policy applies only to the use of the Massachusetts State Lottery web site. Other web sites operated by state agencies have individual privacy polcies tailored to the interactions available through each site. On the Lottery’s web site, you may also see links to external web sites. We strongly suggest that you read the privacy policies for each web site that you visit.

**A Privacy Partnership**

Your privacy with respect to the use of this web site results from a partnership between the Commonwealth and you, the user. At this web site, we attempt to protect your privacy to the maximum extent possible. However, because some of the information that we receive through this web site is subject to the [Public Records Law, Massachusetts General Laws Chapter 66, Section 10,](http://www.mass.gov/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) we cannot ensure absolute privacy. Information that you provide to us through this site may be made available to members of the public under that law. This policy informs you of the information that we collect from you at this site, what we do with it, to whom it may be disseminated, and how you can access it. Based on this information, you can make an informed choice about your use of this site and whether to share personally identifiable information with us through this site.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We use the term "personally identifiable information" to mean any information that could reasonably be used to identify you, including, but not limited to, your name, address, e-mail address, Social Security number, birth date, bank account information, credit card information, or any combination of other identifying information.

**Information Voluntarily Provided by You**

This site collects voluntary information, including personally identifiable information, from you through online forms that you choose to complete and through the e-mails that you send through this site. 

**Information Automatically Collected and Stored by this Site**

The Lottery may place a “cookie”, a small text file, on a visitor’s hard drive. This cookie contains a randomly generated user ID in order to track unique site visits. The Lottery does not uses cookies to store any personal information. This cookie can only be read by Lottery servers and assists us with the statistical analysis necessary to assure site functionality and responsiveness.

This site does collect and store indefinitely your Internet Protocol ("IP") address (which does not identify you as an individual), as well as information about the date and time of your visit, whether a file you have requested exists, and how many "bytes" of information were transmitted to you over the Web from this site. We use your IP address to assess the frequency of visits to this site and the popularity of its various pages and functions. We will not attempt to match any personally identifiable information that you provide to us with your IP address, unless there are reasonable grounds to believe that doing so would provide information that is relevant and material to a criminal investigation.

**Dissemination of Your Personally Identifiable Information**

We do not sell any personally identifiable information collected through this web site or submitted to the Lottery in conjunction with using functions on the web site, and there is no direct or online public access to the information. However, once you voluntarily submit personally identifiable information to us, its dissemination is governed by the [Public Records Law](http://www.mass.gov/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm), the [Massachusetts General Laws Chapter 66A ](http://www.mass.gov/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm)(Fair Information Practices Act) , [Executive Order 412](http://www.lawlib.state.ma.us/ExecOrders/eo412.txt), and other applicable laws and regulations. In addition, dissemination of information collected through this web site may be made in the course of a law enbforcement investigation, or through compulsory legal process. For these reasons, part or all of the information you send us may be disseminated.

In addition, the information that you voluntarily submit will be disclosed only to Commonwealth employees or officials, or those under contract with the Commonwealth, with a "need to know" for purposes of fulfilling their job responsibilities. They will only use the information to answer your questions, respond to any requests for assistance, and fulfill the Commonwealth's legal obligations. Where appropriate, we may provide the information submitted by you to the person or company that is the subject of your inquiry, or to a government agency responsible for the matters referred to in your communication.

**Your Access and Opportunity to Correct**

The [Public Records Law](http://www.mass.gov/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) and the [Fair Information Practices Act](http://www.mass.gov/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) provide you certain rights to get information about you that is in our records. To learn more about the circumstances under which you can get and correct this information, please click on the above references to these laws.

**Security**

Because this site does not encrypt incoming e-mail, you should not send information that you consider highly sensitive through this Web site. We use standard security measures to ensure that your personally identifiable information is not lost, misused, altered, or unintentionally destroyed. We also use software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits.

**Special Protections Against Misuse Of Personally Identifiable Information Within Commonwealth Offices**

In 1999 [Executive Order 412](http://www.lawlib.state.ma.us/ExecOrders/eo412.txt) was issued, which enhanced the privacy protection given to any information about you as a named individual held by the Executive Department of state government. [Executive Order 412 ](http://www.lawlib.state.ma.us/ExecOrders/eo412.txt)limits the collection and dissemination of personally identifiable information within the Executive Department. This site complies with [Executive Order 412](http://www.lawlib.state.ma.us/ExecOrders/eo412.txt), so all of the personally identifiable information that you submit to this site is given the privacy protections set forth in [Executive Order 412](http://www.lawlib.state.ma.us/ExecOrders/eo412.txt).

**Policy Changes**

We will post substantive changes to this policy at least 7 days before they take effect. Any information we collect under the current privacy policy will remain subject to the terms of this policy. After any changes take effect, all new information we collect, if any, will be subject to the new policy.

**Contact Information**

For questions about your privacy while using this Web site, please contact us at [webmaster@masslottery.com](mailto:webmaster@masslottery.com)

### Definitions

**Cookies** are files that a Web site can place on your computer. A cookie file contains unique information that a Web site can use to track such things as your password, lists of Web pages you have visited, and the date when you last looked at a specific Web page, or to identify your session at a particular Web site. A cookie file allows the Web site to recognize you as you click through pages on the site and when you later revisit the site. A Web site can use cookies to "remember" your preferences, and to record your browsing behavior on the Web. Although you can prevent Web sites from placing cookies on your computer by using your browser's preference menu, disabling cookies may affect your ability to view or interact with some Web sites.

An **"Internet Protocol Address" or "IP Address"** is a series of numbers that identifies each computer and machine connected to the Internet. An IP address enables a server on a computer network to send you the file that you have requested on the Internet. The IP address disclosed to us may identify the computer from which you are accessing the Internet, or a server owned by your Internet Service Provider. Because it is machine-specific, rather than person-specific, an IP address is not, in and of itself, personally identifiable information.
